João Carrasco

□ carrascojp@outlook.com | □ +1 647 338 8943 | ♥ Toronto, Ontario, CA
 □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/joao-carrasco/ | ♥ https://github.com/jpcrs/

About me _

As a developer, I prioritize simple solutions over over-engineered ones. I have experience working on diverse projects in various industries, including Telecom, Banking, IoT, and Networking, with a focus on backend engineering. In addition to my professional work, programming is also a hobby of mine, and I enjoy exploring new technologies and messing with reverse engineering. Beyond programming, I spend my time reading, learning music, playing, and spending time with friends.

Work Experience

Akamai Technologies (Previously Asavie, acquired Oct 2020)

Dublin, IE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2018 – Aug 2022

- Designed, provisioned, built, and maintained highly scalable APIs for Akamai IoT security services using modern .NET
 Core microservices running on Docker/Kubernetes (AKS) and Azure Functions, implementing patterns like CQRS, Event
 Sourcing, and Actor Model concepts. Using mostly Azure and Azure DevOps for CI/CD.
- Led design sessions for system architecture, OpenAPI design, and new feature implementation details.
- Automated cloud resource creation and management using **Pulumi (C# and TypeScript)** and **Terraform**.
- Built and maintained pipelines for automated build/test/deployment of applications using **Azure DevOps**, with automated deployment to **Kubernetes**, **Azure Functions**, and **WebApps** across multiple environments.
- Integrated our systems with centralized solutions for logs, traces, and metrics like Jaeger, ELK, and Grafana.
- Mentored new team members joining the team.
- Technology Stack: ASP.NET Core, Docker, Kubernetes, Pulumi/Terraform, CosmosDB, Azure Functions, Azure Storage Queue, Azure Event Grid, Azure Service Bus, Azure Event Hubs, and more.

Itaú São Paulo, BR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun 2017 – Apr 2018

- Developed and maintained Banco Itaú, ItaúCard and ITI apps, worked mostly with Android but sometimes also with iOS, and developed API's with Node.js. Had some experiences with CI/CD (Jenkins and SonarQube).
- Technology stack: Node.js, Express, Android (EventBus, Retrofit, RxJava), iOS (Objective-C and Swift).

MUTANT BR
São Paulo, BR
FULL STACK ENGINEER
Apr 2017 – Jul 2017

• Developed web systems for NET and Claro, using mainly Microsoft technology stack, **Agile (Scrum)**, TFS for versioning and **SQLServer** for database. Also responsible for creating some Cl jobs using **Jenkins** and **Octopus Deploy**.

TOTVS juriTIs São Paulo, BR

FULL STACK ENGINEER

Jul 2015 – Jan 2017

- Developed web systems for some of the biggest legal offices in Brazil, using mainly Microsoft technology stack, Agile (Scrum), databases with TSQL (SQLServer) and PL/SQL and Crystal Reports for reports.
- Technology stack: ASP.NET MVC5, EF5, WebAPI v2, OData v2, LINQ, SignalR, HangFire, AutoMapper, SimpleInjector, Durandal, KnockoutJS, BreezeJS, JQuery, KendoUI.

Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia de São Paulo

São Paulo, BR

TEACHER ASSISTANT

May 2013 - Mar 2014

• Paid internship during college, responsible for helping in Programming Logic and C Development classes.

Skills

Programming Languages: C#, JavaScript, TypeScript

Technologies: Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, ELK, Pulumi, Terraform, SQL (MS SQLServer, Postgre), No-SQL (CosmosDB, MongoDB)

Used Previously: Clojure, Go, Java, Python

Studying: Rust, F#

Education _

Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia de São Paulo

São Paulo, SP

BACHELOR IN TECHNOLOGY